<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Darin Gordon</title>
    <link>https://dowwie.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Darin Gordon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dowwie.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://dowwie.github.io/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dowwie.github.io/about_me/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The ultimate measure of a man is not where he stands in moments of comfort
and convenience, but where he stands at times of challenge and controversy&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; Martin Luther King Jr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quote resonates deeply with me.  I have a strong sense of community and moral
obligation to act when it is within my power to do so, despite the sacrifices
that are required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, I took a month leave of absence and volunteered for the American
Red Cross, operating a shelter in Louisiana after Hurricane Katrina hit the U.S
in 2005.  Directly participating in the relief effort of a national disaster was
more important than any project I was involved in at that time at Merrill Lynch. Having the
capacity to help and then taking a month unpaid leave of absence to respond to a national
crisis was the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, after climbing a hard-earned career path through the major wall street
investment banks for nearly a decade, I&amp;rsquo;ve re-aligned my career with my core
values.  During my time in financial services, I successfully lead many projects and
initiatives across teams and business divisions in margin, risk management, product development
and IT.  I&amp;rsquo;m now (finally) dedicating all of myself to a mission that I believe will
have a positive, lasting impact in society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;brief-professional-summary:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Brief Professional Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;career:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Career&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darin worked for Bank of America Merrill Lynch prime brokerage as a product development manager supporting the margin financing business. In this role, Darin helped the business grow through the implementation of new margin offerings. For example, Darin led a day trade margining initiative that has created new revenue opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darin worked in the margin risk group of Goldman Sachs Securities prime brokerage where he delivered a real time margin risk monitoring system, was responsible for monitoring event driven risks, performed adhoc risk analysis with members of the global risk team, and coordinated projects with IT.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before working Goldman&amp;rsquo;s margin risk group, Darin worked for Bear Stearns as a member of the risk control group supporting their prime brokerage margin financing business. His primary responsibilities included risk analysis, software development and systems analysis, and project management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Darin graduated from university, he joined the investment management business, Merrill Lynch Investment Managers.  There, Darin worked with the fixed income investments business as a lead developer, systems analyst, project manager, and business liaison. During his time there, he led several initiatives that would ultimately realize a cost savings of over a million dollars for the firm, and enable them to identify more investment opportunities using relative value arbitrage strategies with credit securities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darin graduated from Rutgers / NJIT in 2003 with a bachelors degree in computer science. During undergraduate studies, he spent several years working in a laboratory of computer science research at Rutgers where he gained a wide range of experiences with infrastructural technology roles such as network/system administration and information security. Darin also spent time developing web sites using macromedia flash and html. He interned in the Summers for Merrill Lynch and ultimately accepted an offer to join their technology leadership program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;education:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darin earned a Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science from Rutgers University / NJIT in 2003&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Darin attended the executive MBA program of Duke Fuqua School of Business, class of 2012,
taking leave after two terms to pursue entrepreneurial interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;volunteering-community:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Volunteering, Community&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Python open source software:  author of &lt;a href=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/introducing_yosai&#34;&gt;Yosai&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The American Red Cross&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leukemia Lympoma Society:  Team in Training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Habitat for Humanity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hobbies-interests:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Hobbies, Interests&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I&amp;rsquo;m not working on intellectually challenging work, I&amp;rsquo;m getting my hands
dirty, from DIY home improvement projects to backpacking or camping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some of the best photos that I&amp;rsquo;ve taken using a basic 8MP camera at
places I&amp;rsquo;ve visited in the U.S:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;flexslider left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;ul class=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/aboutme/destinations/acadia.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;Acadia National Park&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;

        &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/aboutme/destinations/bryce.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;Bryce Canyon National Park&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;

        &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/aboutme/destinations/capitolreef.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;Capital Reef National Park&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;

        &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/aboutme/destinations/glacier.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;Glacier National Park&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;

        &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/aboutme/destinations/grandcanyon.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;Grand Canyon National Park&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;

        &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/aboutme/destinations/monumentvalley.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;Monument Valley&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;

        &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/aboutme/destinations/newfoundland.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;Newfoundland&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;

        &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/aboutme/destinations/whitemountainsnh.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;White Mountains, New Hampshire&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;

        &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/aboutme/destinations/yosemite.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;Yosemite National Park&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;

        &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/aboutme/destinations/zion.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;meta&#34;&gt;
            &lt;h1&gt;Zion National Park&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;/li&gt;

    &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Yosai</title>
      <link>https://dowwie.github.io/introducing_yosai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dowwie.github.io/introducing_yosai/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am very pleased to announce the first release of &lt;a href=&#34;http://yosaiproject.github.io/yosai&#34;&gt;Yosai&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yosai is an Apache2-licensed security framework written in Python that provides
&lt;em&gt;industrial strength&lt;/em&gt; authentication, authorization, and session management from
a common API.  It is a port-fork of Apache Shiro: a successful Java project
widely used today.   Apache Shiro is a trusted framework, having evolved over ten
years of battle testing and authored by subject matter experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-yosai:6dd0a7e95f127f8b7720e815198a3233&#34;&gt;Why Yosai?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yosai addresses an unmet need by the Python community:  the need for a
feature-rich security framework that is decoupled from an application, reducing
redundant security-related development across projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application security is a moving target in software development.  It is extremely
important that it be done right and it is increasingly difficult to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to roll your own and you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t try to.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/caveman_wheel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;caveman_wheel&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took this advice by porting a well-established project rather than create
my own from scratch.  Further, Yosai uses other reputable Python projects when
it made sense to do so, such as &lt;code&gt;Passlib&lt;/code&gt; for cryptographic hashing, PyCA&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;cryptography&lt;/code&gt; library for encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this effort, the open source Python community now has a security framework
that it can adapt to a wide range of applications, not just web applications.
When &lt;em&gt;extensions&lt;/em&gt; are written for Yosai, the entire Yosai community will benefit
rather than, say, a subset that uses a specific web framework.  When an &lt;em&gt;integration&lt;/em&gt;
is written, users of a particular application can interface with Yosai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;v-0-1-0-project-good-enough-is-complete:6dd0a7e95f127f8b7720e815198a3233&#34;&gt;v.0.1.0, project &amp;ldquo;Good Enough&amp;rdquo;, is complete&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/no_stone_unturned.png&#34; alt=&#34;stones&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Omnem Movere Lapidem&lt;/em&gt;:  Leave No Stone Unturned&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To leave no stone unturned is to leave nothing undone.  My goal with v0.1.0 was to create something &lt;em&gt;good enough&lt;/em&gt; for a first production release.  Consequently, some java-like &amp;ldquo;design-stones&amp;rdquo; were left unturned.  These stones &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to be left unturned: time and resource constraints did not allow for them to be tended to nor was I absolutely confident that every code path would survive the next iteration of refactoring:  although Apache Shiro is based on more than ten years of battle testing, competing priorities lead the ambitious to accept how things are along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when you see portions of code that kind of smell like Java design, know that
I had to make a tough decision not to spend too much time and effort on every piece. If a design impacts performance or maintenance, though, and it is on a critical path of execution, there&amp;rsquo;s a really good chance that it will eventually be refactored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;acknowledgements:6dd0a7e95f127f8b7720e815198a3233&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Alex Gronholm, Michael Merickel, Stack Overflow, and the Python
IRC channels on Freenode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. and Les Hazlewood:  Thank you for Shiro!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>