<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on Darin Gordon</title>
    <link>https://dowwie.github.io/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on Darin Gordon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 08:02:48 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dowwie.github.io/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ChainAnchor and Public Partnership in Research</title>
      <link>https://dowwie.github.io/public_domain_research/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 08:02:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dowwie.github.io/public_domain_research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;People need to stop and think about the ChainAnchor project without jumping to stark conclusions about its intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ChainAnchor is an experiment born in MIT. The project is lead by Sandy Pentland and company, who have a strong record in pursuing rights online.
Pentland was awarded the &lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/tXgLMj2Weig?t=15m6s&#34;&gt;Brandeis Privacy Award in 2015&lt;/a&gt;.  He and a team are the authors of &lt;a href=&#34;http://enigma.media.mit.edu&#34;&gt;Enigma&lt;/a&gt;.  This is a team that takes ethics seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pentland&amp;rsquo;s group releases papers, as all academics do, to foster review and discussion.  They&amp;rsquo;re not planting a flag and staking a claim as commercial ventures do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the case of blockchains and cryptocurrency, practioners like Peter Todd &lt;em&gt;could&lt;/em&gt; play an important role in that peer review process. However, in this circumstance Todd responded in a public, inflammatory way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider for a moment what an entirely academic-led peer review process would be like if controversial papers such as that about ChainAnchor were publicly attacked and its authors humiliated. This would quickly become an unsafe environment to explore and challenge ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If academia is to partner with practitioners and experts, both groups are going to need to achieve a mutually beneficial arrangement to advance the field together. This is now a case of what such an arrangement &lt;em&gt;would not&lt;/em&gt; look like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the record: I currently have no commercial nor academic interests in this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>