<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tutorials on Darin Gordon</title>
    <link>https://dowwie.github.io/tags/tutorials/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tutorials on Darin Gordon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2016</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://dowwie.github.io/tags/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorials for Learning Rust in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://dowwie.github.io/rust_tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dowwie.github.io/rust_tutorials/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to announce my first Rust tutorial, available through a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.daringordon.com/tutorials-rs/&#34;&gt;general Rust tutorials project&lt;/a&gt;.  The tutorial is intended to help beginners to Rust who are interested in learning Rust concepts through their application.  The subject of the tutorial is my first Rust project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Dowwie/rust-authz&#34;&gt;authz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/tutorials_grey.svg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tutorials project is a &lt;em&gt;community resource&lt;/em&gt;.  The content is largely from documentation, blog posts, and ad-hoc contributions from the Rustacean-leaders at #rust-beginners on irc.mozilla.org.  Since this is a community resource, I encourage contributions of all kinds.  The tutorials project is &lt;em&gt;yours&lt;/em&gt; as much as it is mine.  Author a tutorial and we&amp;rsquo;ll publish it together in the landing page (and move the web site domain).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;center-learning-by-teaching-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt;Learning By Teaching&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a principle of learning that if you would like to learn a subject well, teach it.  This work is a milestone in my learning of Rust because of this principle.  About a month ago, I began to learn Rust.  With a lot of help from the Rust community, I&amp;rsquo;ve released my first library as an open source crate, written a Python extension to the library, and now conclude this chapter by introducing a tutorial based on the library.  Teaching what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned pushed me to go further and connect ideas that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t.  I believe it was a very important step in my learning and development.  It was so valuable of an experience that I feel compelled to encourage anyone reading this to give writing a tutorial a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;center-about-the-tutorial-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt;About the Tutorial&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the tutorial, I chose &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/YosaiProject/yosai/blob/master/yosai/core/authz/authz.py#L37&#34;&gt;code written in Python&lt;/a&gt; that has the potential to become computationally expensive.  The logic isn&amp;rsquo;t too complicated yet the code requires enough concepts that I thought it would be a good entrypoint project.  My goal was to dip a toe in the Rusty water, so to speak.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go swimming (or drown!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you find this work useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>