<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Darin Gordon</title>
    <link>https://dowwie.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Darin Gordon</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2016</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 06:47:41 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://dowwie.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Yosai v0.3</title>
      <link>https://dowwie.github.io/yosai_v03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 06:47:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dowwie.github.io/yosai_v03/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yosai v0.3 was released to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/yosai/0.3.0&#34;&gt;PyPI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yosaiproject.github.io/yosai&#34;&gt;Project Web Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-yosai&#34;&gt;About Yosai&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yosai is an Apache2-licensed security framework written in Python that provides
&lt;em&gt;industrial strength&lt;/em&gt; authentication, authorization, and session management from
a common API.  You can secure &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; kind of Python application with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-highlights&#34;&gt;Release Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A complete second-factor authentication workflow using time-based one-time passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rate limiting / account locking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significant refactoring and optimizations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;center-second-factor-authentication-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt; Second Factor Authentication &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/totp.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;totp_logo&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As of this release, Yosai features native support for Time-based One Time Passwords (TOTP), the
prevailing standard for one-time password authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authenticating a user configured for TOTP authentication involves two steps:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Username / Password Authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One-time Password Authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overview of second-factor authentication was added to Yosai&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://yosaiproject.github.io/yosai/authentication&#34;&gt;authentication
documentation&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve created a &lt;a href=&#34;http://yosaiproject.github.io/yosai/tutorials/totp_tutorial&#34;&gt;complete tutorial&lt;/a&gt;
to help you learn how to use TOTP in your project.  The tutorial guides you
through setup and workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;center-rate-limiting-account-locking-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt; Rate Limiting / Account Locking &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yosai now allows developers to regulate account authentication for any particular
user account by defining a number of maximum allowable authentication attempts.
If a developer defines within yosai&amp;rsquo;s authentication settings an &lt;strong&gt;account_lock_threshold&lt;/strong&gt;,
defining a limit to the total allowable failed attempts during authentication,
account locking is enabled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Assuming account locking is enabled, the moment that the number of failed
authentication attempts exceeds the maximum-allowable threshold, Yosai will lock
the account, prohibiting subsequent authentication regardless of whether
credentials match.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;center-refactoring-and-optimizations-center&#34;&gt;&lt;center&gt; Refactoring and Optimizations &lt;/center&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Refactoring is an iterative process that ought to be undertaken when the benefits
of doing so are sufficient to justify the expenditure of effort required to perform
it. In this case, the ends justified the means:  Yosai v0.3 is leaner, meaner, and
consequently a whole lot more pythonic than prior versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-details&#34;&gt;Project Details&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yosai works with newer versions of python3, specifically py3.4 and newer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yosaiproject&#34;&gt;the Yosai Project on Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;passlib-1-7&#34;&gt;Passlib 1.7&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yosai v0.3 uses Passlib for cryptographic hashing and totp token generation.  This
was made possible by the latest Passlib 1.7 release.  I&amp;rsquo;d like to thank its author,
Eli, for his dedication to the project.  To learn more about this project and the
updates in 1.7, vist &lt;a href=&#34;https://pythonhosted.org/passlib/&#34;&gt;the passlib web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Release highlights:
- Argon2 &amp;amp; Scrypt hash support
- TOTP support
- PBKDF2 now has faster builtin backend, and utilizes other backends where available
- Lots of API cleanups and internal refactoring
- HtpasswdFile reader is now more flexible, and with improved security options.
- Refreshed documentation&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Announcing Yosai v0.2</title>
      <link>https://dowwie.github.io/yosai_v02/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dowwie.github.io/yosai_v02/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Yosai v0.2 was released to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pypi.python.org/pypi/yosai/0.2.0&#34;&gt;PyPI&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://yosaiproject.github.io/yosai&#34;&gt;Project Web Site&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;release-highlights&#34;&gt;Release Highlights&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yosai is ready to be integrated with web applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration and initialization has been streamlined&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Many java-like design patterns were refactored&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yosai and WebYosai APIs&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Major improvements with serialization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;pyramid-yosai&#34;&gt;pyramid_yosai&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pyramid_yosai is the first integration with a web application framework, specifically
the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.trypyramid.com&#34;&gt;Pyramid Web Framework&lt;/a&gt;.  pyramid_yosai was released to
pypi and is ready for use in your projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;monsterrx&#34;&gt;MonsterRX&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/monster_rx_logo.png&#34; alt=&#34;monster_rx&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fully-functioning demonstration of a Yosai-secured pyramid application is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/YosaiProject/monster_rx&#34;&gt;available from github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project is called MonsterRX, as in &amp;ldquo;Monster Prescription&amp;rdquo;.  It&amp;rsquo;s a basic
workflow application for medical prescriptions.  It&amp;rsquo;s intended for Monster use,
exclusively, due to regulations.  These Monsters are very special and have diets
quite different from ours.  In fact, their medicine are jellybeans!  Check out the
project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-yosai&#34;&gt;About Yosai&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yosai is an Apache2-licensed security framework written in Python that provides
&lt;em&gt;industrial strength&lt;/em&gt; authentication, authorization, and session management from
a common API.  You can secure &lt;em&gt;any&lt;/em&gt; kind of Python application with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;python-versions-supported&#34;&gt;Python Versions Supported&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yosai works with newer versions of python3, specifically py3.4 and newer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-yosai-project&#34;&gt;The Yosai Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/yosaiproject&#34;&gt;The Yosai Project&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tutorials for Learning Rust in the Wild</title>
      <link>https://dowwie.github.io/rust_tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dowwie.github.io/rust_tutorials/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;announcement&#34;&gt;Announcement&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am pleased to announce my first Rust tutorial, available through a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.daringordon.com/tutorials-rs/&#34;&gt;general Rust tutorials project&lt;/a&gt;.  The tutorial is intended to help beginners to Rust who are interested in learning Rust concepts through their application.  The subject of the tutorial is my first Rust project, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Dowwie/rust-authz&#34;&gt;authz&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rust-tutorials&#34;&gt;Rust Tutorials&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/tutorials_grey.svg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tutorials project is a &lt;em&gt;community resource&lt;/em&gt;.  The content is largely from documentation, blog posts, and ad-hoc contributions from the Rustacean-leaders at #rust-beginners on irc.mozilla.org.  Since this is a community resource, I encourage contributions of all kinds.  The tutorials project is &lt;em&gt;yours&lt;/em&gt; as much as it is mine.  Author a tutorial and we&amp;rsquo;ll publish it together in the landing page (and move the web site domain).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;learning-by-teaching&#34;&gt;Learning By Teaching&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a principle of learning that if you would like to learn a subject well, teach it.  This work is a milestone in my learning of Rust because of this principle.  About a month ago, I began to learn Rust.  With a lot of help from the Rust community, I&amp;rsquo;ve released my first library as an open source crate, written a Python extension to the library, and now conclude this chapter by introducing a tutorial based on the library.  Teaching what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned pushed me to go further and connect ideas that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t.  I believe it was a very important step in my learning and development.  It was so valuable of an experience that I feel compelled to encourage anyone reading this to give writing a tutorial a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-the-tutorial&#34;&gt;About the Tutorial&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the tutorial, I chose &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/YosaiProject/yosai/blob/master/yosai/core/authz/authz.py#L37&#34;&gt;code written in Python&lt;/a&gt; that has the potential to become computationally expensive.  The logic isn&amp;rsquo;t too complicated yet the code requires enough concepts that I thought it would be a good entrypoint project.  My goal was to dip a toe in the Rusty water, so to speak.  I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go swimming (or drown!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you find this work useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Yosai</title>
      <link>https://dowwie.github.io/introducing_yosai/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2016 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dowwie.github.io/introducing_yosai/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I am very pleased to announce the first release of &lt;a href=&#34;http://yosaiproject.github.io/yosai&#34;&gt;Yosai&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yosai is an Apache2-licensed security framework written in Python that provides
&lt;em&gt;industrial strength&lt;/em&gt; authentication, authorization, and session management from
a common API.  It is a port-fork of Apache Shiro: a successful Java project
widely used today.   Apache Shiro is a trusted framework, having evolved over ten
years of battle testing and authored by subject matter experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-yosai&#34;&gt;Why Yosai?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yosai addresses an unmet need by the Python community:  the need for a
feature-rich security framework that is decoupled from an application, reducing
redundant security-related development across projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application security is a moving target in software development.  It is extremely
important that it be done right and it is increasingly difficult to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s hard to roll your own and you probably shouldn&amp;rsquo;t try to.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/caveman_wheel.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;caveman_wheel&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took this advice by porting a well-established project rather than create
my own from scratch.  Further, Yosai uses other reputable Python projects when
it made sense to do so, such as &lt;code&gt;Passlib&lt;/code&gt; for cryptographic hashing, PyCA&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;cryptography&lt;/code&gt; library for encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through this effort, the open source Python community now has a security framework
that it can adapt to a wide range of applications, not just web applications.
When &lt;em&gt;extensions&lt;/em&gt; are written for Yosai, the entire Yosai community will benefit
rather than, say, a subset that uses a specific web framework.  When an &lt;em&gt;integration&lt;/em&gt;
is written, users of a particular application can interface with Yosai.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;v-0-1-0-project-good-enough-is-complete&#34;&gt;v.0.1.0, project &amp;ldquo;Good Enough&amp;rdquo;, is complete&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://dowwie.github.io/content/images/no_stone_unturned.png&#34; alt=&#34;stones&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Omnem Movere Lapidem&lt;/em&gt;:  Leave No Stone Unturned&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To leave no stone unturned is to leave nothing undone.  My goal with v0.1.0 was to create something &lt;em&gt;good enough&lt;/em&gt; for a first production release.  Consequently, some java-like &amp;ldquo;design-stones&amp;rdquo; were left unturned.  These stones &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to be left unturned: time and resource constraints did not allow for them to be tended to nor was I absolutely confident that every code path would survive the next iteration of refactoring:  although Apache Shiro is based on more than ten years of battle testing, competing priorities lead the ambitious to accept how things are along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, when you see portions of code that kind of smell like Java design, know that
I had to make a tough decision not to spend too much time and effort on every piece. If a design impacts performance or maintenance, though, and it is on a critical path of execution, there&amp;rsquo;s a really good chance that it will eventually be refactored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special thanks to Alex Gronholm, Michael Merickel, Stack Overflow, and the Python
IRC channels on Freenode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.. and Les Hazlewood:  Thank you for Shiro!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>